# SHAWNCONRAD UX Designer

Location: Austell, GA Phone: 678-744-3915 Email: shawn@shawnconrad.com Website: www.shawnconrad.com

#### **PROFILE**

I get a thrill out of wow-ing my clients and team members with pixel perfect responsive and interactive UX design that is intuitive and easy for end users with even basic abilities. I am driven to mock up, prototype, and hand-code modern websites or applications that not only look great but increase ROI and help drive revenue. I have a proven ability to evaluate, learn and master new technologies. I am a high energy team player who has been effective in building team moral with a positive attitude and great enthusiasm.

#### **LANGUAGES & SKILLS**

- User Interface design and User Experience interaction design
- Responsive design
- Axure
- Sketch
- Principle
- Photoshop
- HTML5
- CSS3 and SASS
- Twitter Bootstrap
- Agile and SCRUM experience
- iQuery

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

First Data - Atlanta, GA

11/2016 - Present

### Web Developer/Designer

- Defined user interaction models and created UI specifications.
- Used HTML, CSS, and JavaScript development skills and experience.
- Developed and maintained design wireframes, mockups, and specifications as needed.
- Able to communicate scenarios and screen designs to business partners.
- Consulted with Supervisor, Project Managers, colleagues and Clients early in the requirements definitions phase to determine functional specifications for unique systems.
- Provided information to ensure that all parties have a complete understanding of the application and resolved questions of program content, data input and data output requirements.

### Spectechcular - Austell, GA

06/2016 - 11/2016

#### Developer/Owner/Project Manager

- An LLC which I have formed for periodic website & mobile development work during off hours.
- After the completion of the Home Depot contract, this venture was perfect to supplement income and allow me to learn new technologies
- Gained experience in marketing, price quoting and sales.

PORTFOLIO: www.shawnconrad.com/#/portfolio

# SHAWNCONRAD UX Designer

Increased my understanding of customer relations and ease-of-use that translates into revenue

The Home Depot - Atlanta, GA 12/2014 - 05/2016 Web Developer

- UI Developer handling all UI components of numerous web applications for The Home Depot.
- Used my know of clean design and user experience to improve user interfaces for existing and new applications
- Worked on Home Depot's most major application used at all stores Store PC Menu
- Was one of only 5 team members that worked on the new Chrome version of Store PC Menu which is due to roll out in 2017
- Revised internally used application user interfaces for company employess and IT staff
- Technology used includes HTML5, CSS3, LESS, Angular v1, jQuery, Bootstrap, Material Design

**WebMD - Atlanta, GA** 07/2014 - 11/2014 **Web Developer** 

- Contracting consultant collaborating with other developers, product managers, designers, and producers to re-skin the WebMD web site while meeting the project's deadlines.
- Details include developing cross-browser, functional web pages and modules using front-end web languages such as HTML5, CSS3, and jQuery.

## The Coca-Cola Company - Atlanta, GA

11/2013 - 7/2014

### **UI Developer**

- Responsible for Freestyle Project to develop E-commerce SAP solution aka CokeSmart.
- Designed and developed from wireframes through handing coding in order to revamp several existing B2B website pages.
- Worked remotely towards end of project
- Used HTML5, CSS3, jQuery and JavaScript as needed to provide implementation of B2B applications.

#### Day Three Media - Kennesaw GA

12/2013 - 5/2014

#### **Lead Web Developer**

- Lead Web Developer on a team of three. Develop customized responsive Wordpress websites for mid-level business clients.
- Hand coding of HTML, CSS, and very light PHP.

PORTFOLIO: www.shawnconrad.com/#/portfolio

# SHAWNCONRAD UX Designer

# National Builder Supply - Austell GA 05/2013 - 11/2013 Web Designer

- Web Designer on a team of eight. Developed design comps and layouts for campaign assets, web banners, blogs, social media features, and display ads.
- Technology used was Photoshop, HTML, and CSS.

# Freshco Media - Austell GA 11/2007 – 04/2013 Web Designer & CEO

- Company owner, Web Designer, and Sound Designer consultant.
- Began at company doing majority of sound design projects listed below.
- In early 2011, more work began coming in for website design, utilizing Photoshop for wireframing and website design. Once wireframes and designs were approved, I built websites using HTML, CSS, Zurb Foundation, and jQuery. These projects were done remotely for small business clients.

## Sound Designer / Mixer

11/2007-07/2012

Using Avid Pro Tools, responsibilities included recording voice actors, adding sound effects to commercials and television shows, blending in approved music and mixing all of those elements together for the final sound of the project. Past project include but are not limited to the following...

- Freelance Sound Designer: TNT, TBS, Cartoon Network: 2010 2012
- Sound Mixer for Tyler Perry's House of Payne and Meet The Browns: 2009
- Adjunct teach at School of Audio Engineering Atlanta 2009
- Freelance Sound Designer at Magick Lantern Studio: 2008 2009
- Freelance Sound Mixer for television commercials and reality TV shows: 2007

#### **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

**Art Institute of Pittsburgh**, Online – BS, Web Design & Interactive Media (on hiatus) **New York College of Technology**, Brooklyn, New York - AAS, Art & Advertising Design